<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>scientific-spirituality | Vishal Kaushal</title>
    <link>https://vishkaush.github.io/tags/scientific-spirituality/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://vishkaush.github.io/tags/scientific-spirituality/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>scientific-spirituality</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 Vishal Kaushal</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 16:03:01 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://vishkaush.github.io/img/VK.jpg</url>
      <title>scientific-spirituality</title>
      <link>https://vishkaush.github.io/tags/scientific-spirituality/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Science and (Non)Science</title>
      <link>https://vishkaush.github.io/post/so-called-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 16:03:01 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishkaush.github.io/post/so-called-science/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Science&lt;/em&gt;, (from the Latin word scientia, meaning &amp;ldquo;knowledge&amp;rdquo;), is a systematic enterprise that builds and organizes knowledge in the form of testable explanations and predictions about the universe. [Source: Wikipedia]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being open to accept any of the possible hypotheses given sufficient evidence without being attached to a specific hypothesis (read dogma) driven by ulterior motives is the very essence of any scientific study.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this light, I hope the below is only a mockery of &amp;ldquo;non-science&amp;rdquo; and true science better be genuine and open in its intent and findings as upheld by &lt;strong&gt;some of the renowned scientists of the past&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;non-science.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;non science&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;einstein.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;einstein&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;kelvin.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;kelvin&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;newton.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;newton&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;sagan.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;sagan&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How old are we?</title>
      <link>https://vishkaush.github.io/post/human/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 17:13:12 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishkaush.github.io/post/human/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/UagdU1qYnC8&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Contrary to the popular belief (thanks to Mr. Darwin) that modern humans evolved in East Africa 200,000 years ago, fossils recovered from an old mine on a desolate mountain in Morocco indicate that we are &amp;ldquo;older&amp;rdquo;. Though this has come as a shock to many faithful followers of Charles Darwin, the believers continue to (rationally) believe that God has created us all. The ancient texts of wisdom like The Holy Bible, The Quran, The Bhagavvd Gita, The Srimad Bhagvatam and the likes - all maintain and explain this understanding. Bhagavad Gita infact does refer to evolution - not of body, but that of the consciousness. A living entity evolves in its consciousness as it goes around in its journey through the various species of life, pretty much like a child who &amp;ldquo;evolves&amp;rdquo; from grade 5 to grade 6. The classrooms don&amp;rsquo;t evolve, the child does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is now enough evidence against the theory of evolution. Darwin proposed a theory in the famous &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.literature.org/authors/darwin-charles/the-origin-of-species/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Origin of Species&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;, but he has two entire chapters, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.literature.org/authors/darwin-charles/the-origin-of-species/chapter-06.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Difficulties on Theory&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.literature.org/authors/darwin-charles/the-origin-of-species/chapter-09.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;On the imperfection of the Geological Record&lt;/a&gt;, that state that the evidence his theory required was missing. He assumed the evidence would be there some time in the future and his faithful followers are still searching for those. Meanwhile, I encourage you to go through these resources and see for yourself what makes more sense - evolution or creation!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.naturesiq.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Nature&amp;rsquo;s IQ&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.naturesiqfilm.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Nature&amp;rsquo;s IQ - The Film&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://harunyahya.com/en/76/categories/collapse-of-the-theory-of&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Collapse of Darwinism&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forbiddenarcheology.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Forbidden Archaeology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>(Anti) Social Media</title>
      <link>https://vishkaush.github.io/post/anti-social-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 17:07:32 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishkaush.github.io/post/anti-social-media/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I bumped into an elderly co-passenger&lt;/em&gt; in train the other day who was struggling to manage his contacts on phone. Sensing that I am a technology guy (due to my laptop, I guess) he asked me for help. Now for any of us who have grown in the word of technology, this is certainly not the most difficult problem to solve. Sure enough, I helped him out and was satisfied to see a smile on his face. In appreciation, he spoke - &lt;strong&gt;&amp;lsquo;how wonderful is it that the world has become smaller due to technology!&amp;rsquo;&lt;/strong&gt;. Before I could decide whether to agree or disagree, my station was waiting for me and I stepped out of the train.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Has technology made the world smaller? Or bigger? Earlier in villages, away from technology, everybody would know each other well and share their joys and sorrows together. Today, yes, we can talk to our friend on the other side of the globe, but do we know or care to know who is our neighbor? Haven&amp;rsquo;t the distances with our neighbors, with our family members, with each other, increased?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Search for &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;social media depression&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;social media loneliness&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; in &lt;a href=&#34;www.google.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt; and you will see tons of scientific studies and news articles telling how &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;anti&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;-social the &lt;em&gt;social&lt;/em&gt; media has become. Here is a sample:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.telegraph.co.uk/technology/2017/03/06/much-social-media-increases-loneliness-envy-study/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Too much social media &amp;lsquo;increases loneliness and envy&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://socialmediaweek.org/blog/2015/06/social-media-even-lonely/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Why Social Makes Us Even More Lonely&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2017-03/uops-msc022817.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;More social connection online tied to increasing feelings of isolation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.psychologytoday.com/blog/why-we-worry/201612/social-media-loneliness-and-anxiety-in-young-people&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Social Media, Loneliness, and Anxiety in Young People&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.psychologytoday.com/blog/the-practical-professor/201507/the-loneliness-social-media-part-one&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The loneliness of Social Media&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/aj-agrawal/are-social-networks-causi_b_12396080.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Are Social Networks Causing Loneliness Among Teens?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;the list goes on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;lonely.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;lonely cartoon&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We are people. We need people.&lt;/em&gt; How wealthy you are, is determined by number of things you have that money can&amp;rsquo;t buy. It is relationships that make us happy. People are to be loved, objects are to be used. Unfortunately, we have come far, so far, that objects are being loved and people are being used. Our capacity and willingness to deal with inter-personal differences has got so reduced that we prefer texting over calling, we prefer &lt;a href=&#34;www.facebook.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; friends over real friends. Social media began well, with a lot of promises, but has only ended up leaving many lonelier than ever before. Of course, social media in itself is not good or bad. When one realizes that life is bigger and more real than social media, when one recognizes ones spiritual identity, one is able to use technology as one&amp;rsquo;s servant and doesn&amp;rsquo;t end up becoming its slave!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A bug in fMRI software could invalidate 15 years of brain research</title>
      <link>https://vishkaush.github.io/post/bug-in-fmri-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2016 18:01:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishkaush.github.io/post/bug-in-fmri-software/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not that I like to condemn our scientific and technological advancement (as a research scholar at IIT Bombay I myself am full time into it) but I want to make a point that when people label faith (in God/spirituality) as unscientific, they may be failing to understand that what is &amp;ldquo;scientific&amp;rdquo; also demands some kind of faith, if you understand what I mean. According to a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sciencealert.com/a-bug-in-fmri-software-could-invalidate-decades-of-brain-research-scientists-discover&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;recent post in science alert&lt;/a&gt;, a bug in fMRI software could invalidate 15 years of brain research! If this (unfortunately) turns out to be true, what would you call all past decisions made based on these functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI) reports - scientific or made in good &amp;ldquo;faith&amp;rdquo; on &amp;ldquo;science&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question is thus not about &lt;strong&gt;faith or science&lt;/strong&gt; but about &lt;strong&gt;logical or reasonable faith vs blind faith.&lt;/strong&gt; in whatever we come across - be it science or spirituality. A genuine scientist would do good to not outrightly label spirituality as something which demands faith and anything scientific as something to do nothing with faith.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life = Soul, not Heart - Man goes 555 days without one!!</title>
      <link>https://vishkaush.github.io/post/life-soul-heart/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 17:51:05 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishkaush.github.io/post/life-soul-heart/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According to the Supreme Personality of Godhead Shri Krishna in Bhagavad Gita &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vedabase.com/en/bg/18/61&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;18.61&lt;/a&gt;, this body is like a machine, with various organs equivalent to different parts/instruments of the machine. Else where in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vedabase.com/en/bg/2/20&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2.20&lt;/a&gt; He describes the driver or the operator of the machine as us, the living beings, the spirit soul which is indestructible. Interestingly, the following recent news is inline with the above facts mentioned in Bhagavd Gita. Do read and share! &lt;a href=&#34;http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/home/science/25-year-old-goes-555-days-without-a-heart/articleshow/52714587.cms?utm_source=newsletter&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_campaign=digest_section&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;25-year old goes 555 days without a heart!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who should get the Turing Award? You decide</title>
      <link>https://vishkaush.github.io/post/turing-award/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 17:31:37 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishkaush.github.io/post/turing-award/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here is another clue of amazing design in nature - and so close to us! Read on.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lancaster.ac.uk/news/articles/2014/unbreakable-security-codes-inspired-by-nature-/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Unbreakable&amp;rdquo; security codes inspired by nature&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intelligent Design: God&#39;s Fingerprint</title>
      <link>https://vishkaush.github.io/post/intelligent-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 17:13:12 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishkaush.github.io/post/intelligent-design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Remember the famous Fibonacci Sequence you heard of back in school? Watch this video and be amazed at the intelligence of God behind this creation:

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/7Uo4Oond1e8&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
