<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>events | Vishal Kaushal</title>
    <link>https://vishkaush.github.io/tags/events/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://vishkaush.github.io/tags/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>events</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 Vishal Kaushal</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 16:03:01 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://vishkaush.github.io/img/VK.jpg</url>
      <title>events</title>
      <link>https://vishkaush.github.io/tags/events/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>All India Heads of Police Communication Conference</title>
      <link>https://vishkaush.github.io/post/heads-of-police/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 16:03:01 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishkaush.github.io/post/heads-of-police/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Attended the All India Heads of Police Communication conference held at Vigyan Bhawan, New Delhi on 19th and 20th November 2018. I was one of the delegates representing NCETIS (National Center of Excellence in Technology for Internal Security), IITB and was there to showcase some of the product prototypes we have developed to the heads of police from across several states. It was an awesome conference to be a part of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;hop1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;hop1&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;hop2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;hop2&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India International Security Expo</title>
      <link>https://vishkaush.github.io/post/security-expo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 16:03:01 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishkaush.github.io/post/security-expo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another event where I represented NCETIS, IIT Bombay to showcase our product prototypes in the area of automatic analysis of videos for security applications. This was held from 5th to 7th October 2017 and was attended by the who&amp;rsquo;s who in the security space both from the government and from the industry. Seen in the picture is me giving a demonstration to &lt;strong&gt;Shri Kiran Rijiju&lt;/strong&gt;, the then Minister of State for Home Affairs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;security-2.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;two&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;security-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;one&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three days with the Indian Army</title>
      <link>https://vishkaush.github.io/post/army2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2017 16:03:01 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishkaush.github.io/post/army2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is quite happening to pursue PhD at IITB. Here is an example. In the capacity of a research assistant I work on several projects with my PhD advisor, Prof. Ganesh Ramakrishnan. One of the projects, &lt;em&gt;SurakshaVyuha&lt;/em&gt; is about detecting certain events of interest in real-time from the live feeds coming from surveillance cameras. To demonstrate the prototype developed and to further understand the requirements from the horse&amp;rsquo;s mouth, I and my advisor went to an army location near the LoC (&lt;strong&gt;yes, the LoC!&lt;/strong&gt;). This was in December 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was my first experience (and I must say only one of its kind) to stay in one of the brigade head quarters getting to interact with the officers as well as jawans posted there. I was really impressed with their hospitality. Their discipline, their comradry, their organization, their endurance, and above all, their spirit - all par excellence. Came back with a lot of respect for our army in my heart than ever before. &lt;strong&gt;Jai Hind!!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;army3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;army2&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nVidia GTCx India 2016</title>
      <link>https://vishkaush.github.io/post/nvidia-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2016 16:03:01 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishkaush.github.io/post/nvidia-workshop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Attended GTCx India 2016 organized by nVidia on December 6th at Renaissance Convention Centre, Powai, Mumbai. Checkout the keynote sessions &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VLufuchl3Bg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;nvidia1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;one&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;nvidia2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;two&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer School on Deep Learning for Computer Vision</title>
      <link>https://vishkaush.github.io/post/ssdlcv/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 18:03:15 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishkaush.github.io/post/ssdlcv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am currently in Hyderabad attending a 6-day &lt;a href=&#34;http://cvit.iiit.ac.in/summerschool/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;summer school on deep learning for computer vision&lt;/a&gt; organized by Center for Visual Information Technology, IIIT Hyderabad. Couldn&amp;rsquo;t have asked for a better start to my PhD - with renowned speakers presenting the state-of-the-art in this space and with lots of hand on lab sessions. If you are interested in deep learning in general and in deep learning for computer vision in particular, do checkout this &lt;a href=&#34;http://cvit.iiit.ac.in/summerschool/resources.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;wonderful compilation of available resources&lt;/a&gt;. It is quite comprehensive.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mega Youth Festival - Drishti</title>
      <link>https://vishkaush.github.io/post/drishti/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2016 17:44:23 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishkaush.github.io/post/drishti/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mark your calendars for 20th March 2016! A mega youth festival &amp;ldquo;Drishti&amp;rdquo; is going to be organized in Pune which will have feast for eyes, ears, tongue and soul with music, drama, international artists and cultural extravaganza. It will be organized around the theme &amp;ldquo;Bharat leads the world&amp;rdquo;. Don&amp;rsquo;t miss! &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/Dyf-1691349364411177/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Here it is on Facebook.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faculty development programme by iGate</title>
      <link>https://vishkaush.github.io/post/igate-fdp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishkaush.github.io/post/igate-fdp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;www.igate.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;iGate&lt;/a&gt; organized a faculty development programme for faculty members across several colleges. I and a few other colleagues of mine represented VIT, Pune. You can see me sitting right at the end of the first row.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
