<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>philosophy | Vishal Kaushal</title>
    <link>https://vishkaush.github.io/tags/philosophy/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://vishkaush.github.io/tags/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>philosophy</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 Vishal Kaushal</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 16:03:01 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://vishkaush.github.io/img/VK.jpg</url>
      <title>philosophy</title>
      <link>https://vishkaush.github.io/tags/philosophy/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>This came to me as an embarrassment</title>
      <link>https://vishkaush.github.io/post/gratitude-kenjale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 16:03:01 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishkaush.github.io/post/gratitude-kenjale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some time back, one of my close family friends, Shri Santosh Kenjale, shared this with me and it was really embarrassing for me to come across this. He has been taking guidance from me on certain matters of life and sees me as his mentor, though elder in age to me. Out of gratitude, he poured out his heart and wrote about me in an article for a magazine. Embarrassing it was, but I had to come to terms with it and I felt really honored, blessed and humbled. Thank you Kenjale ji for writing about me. I pray that I will be able to live upto your expectations and I really thank you for being such a gem. It is said gratitude is the most fundamental quality of a human being and one who is not grateful is considered to be the worst of humans. I have to learn a lot from you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;kenjale.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;gratitude&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do It Anyway</title>
      <link>https://vishkaush.github.io/post/do-it-anyway/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 16:03:01 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishkaush.github.io/post/do-it-anyway/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;People are often unreasonable, irrational, and self-centered.  &lt;em&gt;Forgive them anyway&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are kind, people may accuse you of selfish, ulterior motives.  &lt;em&gt;Be kind anyway&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are successful, you will win some unfaithful friends and some genuine enemies.  &lt;em&gt;Succeed anyway&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are honest and sincere people may deceive you.  &lt;em&gt;Be honest and sincere anyway&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What you spend years creating, others could destroy overnight.  &lt;em&gt;Create anyway&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you find serenity and happiness, some may be jealous.  &lt;em&gt;Be happy anyway&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good you do today, will often be forgotten.  &lt;em&gt;Do good anyway&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give the best you have, and it will never be enough.  &lt;em&gt;Give your best anyway&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the final analysis, it is between you and God.  &lt;em&gt;It was never between you and them anyway&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Attributed to Mother Teresa&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easy and Difficult</title>
      <link>https://vishkaush.github.io/post/easy-difficult/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 16:03:01 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishkaush.github.io/post/easy-difficult/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easy&lt;/strong&gt; is to judge the mistakes of others;
&lt;strong&gt;Difficult&lt;/strong&gt; is to recognize our own mistakes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easy&lt;/strong&gt; is to talk without thinking;
&lt;strong&gt;Difficult&lt;/strong&gt; is to refrain the tongue&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easy&lt;/strong&gt; is to hurt someone who loves us;
&lt;strong&gt;Difficult&lt;/strong&gt; is to heal the wound&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easy&lt;/strong&gt; is to forgive others;
&lt;strong&gt;Difficult&lt;/strong&gt; is to ask for forgiveness&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easy&lt;/strong&gt; is to set the rules;
&lt;strong&gt;Difficult&lt;/strong&gt; is to follow them&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easy&lt;/strong&gt; is to show victory;
&lt;strong&gt;Difficult&lt;/strong&gt; is to assume defeat with dignity&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easy&lt;/strong&gt; is to enjoy life everyday;
&lt;strong&gt;Difficult&lt;/strong&gt; is to give its real value&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easy&lt;/strong&gt; is to say we love;
&lt;strong&gt;Difficult&lt;/strong&gt; is to show it everyday&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easy&lt;/strong&gt; is to criticize others;
&lt;strong&gt;Difficult&lt;/strong&gt; is to improve oneself&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easy&lt;/strong&gt; is to weep for a lost love;
&lt;strong&gt;Difficult&lt;/strong&gt; is to take care of it so not to lose it&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easy&lt;/strong&gt; is to think about improving;
&lt;strong&gt;Difficult&lt;/strong&gt; is to stop thinking and put it into action&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easy&lt;/strong&gt; is to think bad of others;
&lt;strong&gt;Difficult&lt;/strong&gt; is to give them the benefit of doubt&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easy&lt;/strong&gt; is to receive;
&lt;strong&gt;Difficult&lt;/strong&gt; is to give&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easy&lt;/strong&gt; is to keep friendship with words;
&lt;strong&gt;Difficult&lt;/strong&gt; is to keep it with meanings&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Want to become happy?</title>
      <link>https://vishkaush.github.io/post/stay-away-from-misery/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2017 17:13:12 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishkaush.github.io/post/stay-away-from-misery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you one of those who want to become happy? Start by staying away from things which can make you miserable. Somebody has nicely defined &amp;ldquo;misery&amp;rdquo; as &amp;ldquo;you get what you don&amp;rsquo;t want and you don&amp;rsquo;t get what you want&amp;rdquo;. Check out this brilliant video about seven things that can make you miserable. Stay away from them, if you want some happinss in life. Thanks again, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/CGPGrey&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;CGP Grey&lt;/a&gt;!

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/LO1mTELoj6o&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is spirituality nothing more than a fashion?</title>
      <link>https://vishkaush.github.io/post/spirituality-fashion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 17:13:12 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishkaush.github.io/post/spirituality-fashion/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/SBJYCb3nvi4&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Spirituality is the new &lt;strong&gt;buzzword&lt;/strong&gt; of the town. Some see it as a budding career, some delight in expressing their orientation as &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;spiritual but not religious&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;. Some use it to describe any experience which is out of this world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Just what is spirituality?&lt;/strong&gt; Can any and every experience be termed spiritual? Not really. Most of us tend to think that we are human beings with a spiritual dimension to life. Bhagavad Gita however tells that we are spiritual beings, currently in this human body. Spirituality begins with the understanding that we are not this body, but a driver within this body, the spirit soul, part and parcel of God. No wonder, this is how Lord Krishna begins his teachings to Arjuna in the form of Bhagavad Gita.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;bg.png&#34; alt=&#34;bg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>(Anti) Social Media</title>
      <link>https://vishkaush.github.io/post/anti-social-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 17:07:32 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishkaush.github.io/post/anti-social-media/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I bumped into an elderly co-passenger&lt;/em&gt; in train the other day who was struggling to manage his contacts on phone. Sensing that I am a technology guy (due to my laptop, I guess) he asked me for help. Now for any of us who have grown in the word of technology, this is certainly not the most difficult problem to solve. Sure enough, I helped him out and was satisfied to see a smile on his face. In appreciation, he spoke - &lt;strong&gt;&amp;lsquo;how wonderful is it that the world has become smaller due to technology!&amp;rsquo;&lt;/strong&gt;. Before I could decide whether to agree or disagree, my station was waiting for me and I stepped out of the train.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Has technology made the world smaller? Or bigger? Earlier in villages, away from technology, everybody would know each other well and share their joys and sorrows together. Today, yes, we can talk to our friend on the other side of the globe, but do we know or care to know who is our neighbor? Haven&amp;rsquo;t the distances with our neighbors, with our family members, with each other, increased?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Search for &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;social media depression&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;social media loneliness&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; in &lt;a href=&#34;www.google.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt; and you will see tons of scientific studies and news articles telling how &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;anti&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;-social the &lt;em&gt;social&lt;/em&gt; media has become. Here is a sample:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.telegraph.co.uk/technology/2017/03/06/much-social-media-increases-loneliness-envy-study/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Too much social media &amp;lsquo;increases loneliness and envy&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://socialmediaweek.org/blog/2015/06/social-media-even-lonely/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Why Social Makes Us Even More Lonely&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2017-03/uops-msc022817.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;More social connection online tied to increasing feelings of isolation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.psychologytoday.com/blog/why-we-worry/201612/social-media-loneliness-and-anxiety-in-young-people&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Social Media, Loneliness, and Anxiety in Young People&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.psychologytoday.com/blog/the-practical-professor/201507/the-loneliness-social-media-part-one&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The loneliness of Social Media&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/aj-agrawal/are-social-networks-causi_b_12396080.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Are Social Networks Causing Loneliness Among Teens?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;the list goes on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;lonely.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;lonely cartoon&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We are people. We need people.&lt;/em&gt; How wealthy you are, is determined by number of things you have that money can&amp;rsquo;t buy. It is relationships that make us happy. People are to be loved, objects are to be used. Unfortunately, we have come far, so far, that objects are being loved and people are being used. Our capacity and willingness to deal with inter-personal differences has got so reduced that we prefer texting over calling, we prefer &lt;a href=&#34;www.facebook.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; friends over real friends. Social media began well, with a lot of promises, but has only ended up leaving many lonelier than ever before. Of course, social media in itself is not good or bad. When one realizes that life is bigger and more real than social media, when one recognizes ones spiritual identity, one is able to use technology as one&amp;rsquo;s servant and doesn&amp;rsquo;t end up becoming its slave!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My statement of purpose for getting into the PhD program at IITB</title>
      <link>https://vishkaush.github.io/post/sop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 16:03:01 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishkaush.github.io/post/sop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While getting into the PhD program at IITB I was asked to give a &lt;strong&gt;statement of purpose&lt;/strong&gt; as a common practice world wide. I am not sure whether anybody really read it or not, but I really meant what I wrote :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Statement of Purpose (SOP) for admission to the PhD Programme in Computer Science &amp;amp; Engineering at IIT Bombay in the field of Machine Learning/Data Mining/Data Analytics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The role of brain in a human body can never be overstated. Similar, in my opinion, is the role of the intelligentsia in the society. I strongly believe that the best brains in the world should be contributing to the field of research and education and in this way make a tangible contribution to the society. Though I do not claim to be among the best brains in the world, but as an illustrious alumnus of IIT Kharagpur, with numerous awards and achievements to my credit (including the Institute Silver Medal for being the topper at IIT Kharagpur, Star Award for outstanding performance at BMC Software, “VIT Shri” Awards at Vishwakarma Institute of Technology, Pune for being the best teacher) I certainly can compete with them and thus have a strong urge to contribute, especially in areas like governance and security which can have a tremendous impact on society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have done my BTech in CSE from IIT Kharagpur in 2004 after which I worked for six years in Oracle, Bangalore and then for about two years in BMC Software, Pune. The fruit of these eight years in industry came in the form of a calling - to work for a cause bigger than myself. Not wanting to leave Pune, I joined Vishwakarma Institute of Technology, Pune as an Assistant Professor in the Department of Computer Engineering. This was my first step towards returning back to academia. Vishwakarma Institute of Technology is an autonomous college affiliated with University of Pune and is among the premiere colleges in Maharashtra. Because of the need of the hour at that time, I had to pursue my MTech from the same college. People say I am a perfectionist. I agree. Whatever I do, I like to give myself completely to it. Coupled with God&amp;rsquo;s grace, this has turned out to be a great combination so far. Thus during my MTech also I secured first rank in the department as well as in the institute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now after four years of observing the academia closely, I find myself prepared and geared up for taking the next step, which is of pursuing PhD from IIT Bombay. Being a graduate from IIT Kharagpur, doing MTech from Pune University was a situational compromise for me, but I do not have any such constraints right now. Not only IIT Bombay is close to my home at Pune, being one of the best and most sought after institute in the country, it is my destination of choice and I want to leave no stone unturned to be given an opportunity here to prove my mettle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My MTech work was about automatically recognizing user personality from Facebook status updates. I have been working in the area of Data Analytics for a couple of years now (have a couple of publications and have guided several major projects). My projects have included topics like “automated rating in web applications using collective intelligence”, “creating ACO and PSO based classification and clustering modules in Weka”, “group recommendation and community detection in Facebook”, “ask answer service on Facebook” and a few others. I have now developed a strong affinity for Data Analytics, especially its intersection with Machine Learning. Together they have a potential to change the way we live, for better. Working on real world problems which can touch the lives of people is what excites me and I look forward to working on such problems during my PhD. Given an opportunity, I am confident of making a significant contribution to the field, to IIT Bombay, to our nation, to our society and to the world at large.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are You Thinking?</title>
      <link>https://vishkaush.github.io/post/are-you-thinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2015 17:40:41 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishkaush.github.io/post/are-you-thinking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is said, &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;culture is like blood&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;. Blood is arguably one of the most important things in our body, yet we do not realize its presence/value unless we start losing it. Much the same way, culture is a vital element of the social fabric, but we do not realize its value unless we see the effects of its degradation. In this connection, several years back I had come across this post and would like to share it again here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I hope this catches YOU the way it caught me!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In light of the many perversions and jokes we send along to one another for a laugh, this is a little different: This joke today is not intended to be a joke, it&amp;rsquo;s not intended to be funny, it&amp;rsquo;s intended to get you thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A prominent American&amp;rsquo;s daughter was interviewed on the Early Show and Jane Clayson asked her &amp;ldquo;How could God let something like this happen?&amp;rdquo; (Regarding the attacks on September 11)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anne Graham gave an extremely profound and insightful response.
She said, &amp;ldquo;I believe God is deeply saddened by this, just as we are, but for years we&amp;rsquo;ve been telling God to get out of our schools, to get out of our government and to get out of our lives. And being the gentleman He is,I believe He has calmly backed out. How can we expect God to give us His blessing and His protection if we demand He leave us alone?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In light of recent events&amp;hellip;terrorists attack, school shootings, etc, I think it started when Madeleine Murray O&amp;rsquo;Hare (she was murdered, her body found recently) complained she didn&amp;rsquo;t want prayer in our schools, and we said OK. Then someone said you better not read the Bible in school&amp;hellip;the Bible says thou shalt not kill, thou shalt not steal, and love your neighbor as yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And we said OK.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then Dr. Benjamin Spock said we shouldn&amp;rsquo;t spank our children when they misbehave because their little personalities would be warped and we might damage their self-esteem (Dr. Spock&amp;rsquo;s son committed suicide). We said an expert should know what he&amp;rsquo;s talking about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And we said OK.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then someone said teachers and principals better not discipline our children when they misbehave. The school administrators said no faculty member in this school better touch a student when they misbehave because we don&amp;rsquo;t want any bad publicity, and we surely don&amp;rsquo;t want to be sued (there&amp;rsquo;s a big difference between disciplining, touching, beating, smacking, humiliating, kicking, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And we said OK.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then someone said, let&amp;rsquo;s let our daughters have abortions if they want, and they won&amp;rsquo;t even have to tell their parents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And we said OK.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then some wise school board member said, since boys will be boys and they&amp;rsquo;re going to do it anyway, let&amp;rsquo;s give our sons all the condoms they want so they can have all the fun they desire, and we won&amp;rsquo;t have to tell their parents they got them at school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And we said OK.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then some of our top elected officials said it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter what we do in private as long as we do our jobs. Agreeing with them, we said it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter to me what anyone, including the President, does in private as long as I have a job and the economy is good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then someone said let&amp;rsquo;s print magazines with pictures of nude women and call it wholesome, down-to-earth appreciation for the beauty of the female body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And we said OK.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then someone else took that appreciation a step further and published pictures of nude children and then further again by making them available on the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And we said OK, they&amp;rsquo;re entitled to free speech.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then the entertainment industry said, let&amp;rsquo;s make TV shows and movies that promote profanity, violence, and illicit sex. Let&amp;rsquo;s record music that encourages rape, drugs, murder, suicide, and satanic themes. And we said it&amp;rsquo;s just entertainment, it has no adverse effect, nobody takes it seriously anyway, so go right ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we&amp;rsquo;re asking ourselves why our children have no conscience, why they don&amp;rsquo;t know right from wrong, and why it doesn&amp;rsquo;t bother them to kill strangers, their classmates, and themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably, if we think about it long and hard enough, we can figure it out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has a great deal to do with &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;WE REAP WHAT WE SOW.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Funny how simple it is for people to trash God and then wonder why the world&amp;rsquo;s going to hell. Funny how we believe what the newspapers say, but question what the Bible says.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Funny how you can send &amp;lsquo;jokes&amp;rsquo; through e-mail and they spread like wildfire, but when you start sending messages regarding the Lord, people think twice about sharing. Funny how lewd, crude, vulgar and obscene articles pass freely through cyberspace, but public discussion of God is suppressed in the school and workplace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you laughing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Funny how when you forward this message, you will not send it to many on your address list because you&amp;rsquo;re not sure what they believe, or what they will think of you for sending it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Funny how we can be more worried about what other people think of us than what God thinks of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pass it on if you think it has merit. If not then just discard it&amp;hellip; No one will know you did. But, if you discard this thought process, don&amp;rsquo;t sit back and complain about what bad shape the world is in!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are you thinking?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
