<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vishal Kaushal</title>
    <link>https://vishkaush.github.io/authors/admin/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://vishkaush.github.io/authors/admin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Vishal Kaushal</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 Vishal Kaushal</copyright>
    <image>
      <url>https://vishkaush.github.io/img/VK.jpg</url>
      <title>Vishal Kaushal</title>
      <link>https://vishkaush.github.io/authors/admin/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://vishkaush.github.io/authors/admin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishkaush.github.io/authors/admin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am a &lt;strong&gt;research scholar&lt;/strong&gt; pursuing PhD in Machine Learning for Computer Vision at the Department of Computer Science and Engineering, &lt;strong&gt;IIT Bombay&lt;/strong&gt; since 2016 and a &lt;strong&gt;ML consultant&lt;/strong&gt;. I am also a recipient of &lt;a href=&#34;www.ekal.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ekal Fellowship&lt;/a&gt;. My areas of interest include &lt;strong&gt;machine learning and computer vision with human-in-the-loop and applying machine (deep) learning to automated analysis of videos in general and summarization in particular&lt;/strong&gt;. From 2004 to 2016 I have had 12 years of professional experience working in Oracle India Pvt Ltd (product design and development), BMC Software (R&amp;amp;D for incubation) and Vishwakarma Institute of Technology (faculty). I passed out of &lt;strong&gt;IIT Kharagpur&lt;/strong&gt; in 2004 with BTech (Hons) in CSE and an &lt;strong&gt;Institute Silver Medal&lt;/strong&gt; for topping the class. You can find my resume &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1dujsPp5VJMcW5BqGHdcV2LCkniG_phd6VYC8SxmLjsI/edit#heading=h.ix26pqvpqkb8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides my profession, I am actively involved in social welfare activities. I am serving as the chairman of the &lt;strong&gt;Vedic Oasis for Inspiration, Culture and Education (VOICE)&lt;/strong&gt;, a voluntary youth forum with a motto of &lt;em&gt;“Rekindling Wisdom, Reviving Love”&lt;/em&gt;. In particular, I volunteer my time for spreading the timeless scientific wisdom present in the ancient texts like the Bhagavad Gita, the Quran, the Bible and in other such ancient and contemporary classics, making them relevant to the modern life.  I myself have been a student and a practitioner of Bhagavad Gita for about two decades now. By God&amp;rsquo;s grace I have been appreciated for my &lt;strong&gt;motivational talks on personality development, lifestyle management and leadership&lt;/strong&gt;. Over the years I have been invited to deliver several such seminars to employees in various corporates and students in various premiere institutes of the country.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
